Hi, standing here waiting for today's lesson to begin a story came to mind
站在这里等待课程开始我想到了一个故事
and it was a story of a foreman yelling down into a excavation
一个领班对着下面正在进行挖掘工作的工人喊道：
How many of your men down there?
你们一共有多少人在下面
and the reply came back, 3
3个人， 底下的人回应
and he said, okay, half of you, come on up
领班说道：好的，一半的人上来
now, with that funny story, I would like to launch today's lesson
跟着这个有趣的故事， 我想开始今天的课程
which could be, I guess some would call, all whatever you would like to pick
我猜想，有的人会说
realness is in the eyes of the beholder
眼见为实
the question being of course, that when you talk about taking one half of three people
问题在于， 当你在讨论三个人中的一个半的时候
well, let's put it this way
让我们这样说
who wouldn't like to see the answer, on the other hand,
谁不想看看答案 ，从另一个角度来说
to take three inches, and say let's divide that into two equal parts
将3英寸分成两等分
there is a case where the answer does happen to make sense
在这里答案是合理的
now, today you see, we are going to talk about a new face of our course called the complex numbers
现在， 我们将开始讨论复数
the complex numbers happen to be a delightful topic
复数正好是一个有趣的话题
from the point of view that on the one hand, they offer a great deal of enrichment in pure mathematics
一方面，它极大地丰富了纯数学
and on the other hand, they contribute a great deal to our physical understanding of reality
另一方面，它也给我们对于物理世界的理解贡献颇多
now, to launch into this, let's get right into the topic
现在， 让我们进入主题
I call today's lesson, the complex numbers
我把今天的课程叫做， 复数
and going back to my openning hilarious story
回到开场的搞笑故事
what was saying is that the only numbers that we knew were the integers
那个故事所讲的是我们唯一知道的数是整数
and we were given the equation 2x = 3
我们拿到方程 2x = 3
- and notice that in terms of integers, the equation makes sense, because 2 and 3 happen to be integers
注意到，对于整数来说，这个方程是合理的，因为2跟3都是整数
we're looking for to solve this equation. And the question is, does this equation
have a solution?
我们想解这个方程，问题是，这个方程有解吗
The answer is it only has a solution provided that you want to invent numbers which are not integers.
答案是，它只在我们发明整数以外的数的情况下才有解
In other words, this does not have a solution if we insist that the answer be an integer.
换句话说，当我们希望答案是整数的时候这个方程无解
But if we're willing to invent a new batch of numbers called the fractions or the rational numbers,
但是如果我们可以发明一种新的数，叫做分数或者实数
then this equation will have a solution
那么这个方程会有解
Do we want this to have solutions? Well, sometimes there are meaningful situations in which it's meaningful to solve this equation, other times when it isn't.
我们希望有解吗？ 有的情况下这个方程有有意义的解，有的情况下没有
Again, the story of going into the bank and into the post office and asking for $0.03 worth of $0.02 stamps.
这又是去邮局拿价值3美分的2美分邮票的故事了
And we can think of all sorts of hilarious ways of embellishing this story.
我们可以用各种搞笑的方法编这种故事
Going on further, though, let's take what ultimately became known as the "Real Numbers."
更进一步，我们看看“实数”，
And I'm going to put this in quotation marks. Because even though these are genuinely called the Real Numbers,
我用引号来说实数，因为虽然它们被称作实数
they are no more
real than the integers were real.
它们并不比整数更真实
By definition, a Real Number is simply any number whose square is non
negative
从定义上讲，实数是任何平方非负的数
Assuming that to be the definition of real numbers
依照实数的定义
we come to the equation x squared equals minus 1
我们看到方程x^2 == -1
We say,
does this equation have a solution?
我们说，这个方程有解吗
And the answer is if we insist that the solution has to be a real number
答案是，如果我们坚持方程的解必须是实数
the
answer, obviously, is that this does not have a solution
答案明显是，这个方程无解
Because the definition of a real number is that it's square
cannot be negative, and this says that x squared is minus 1
因为定义中实数的平方非负，而这里说实数平方是-1
So either we must say that this equation does not
have solutions
所以我们要么说，这个方程没有解
Or if we want it to have solutions, we must invent an extension of the number system. We must
extend the real numbers
或者如果我们希望方程有解，我们必须拓展我们的数字系统，我们必须扩展实数
in the same way that if we wanted this equation to have a solution, we had to extend
the integers
就像当我们想要这个方程有解的话我们必须扩充整数一样
The extension of the integers that was necessary to solve this equation
为了解这个方程需要的对整数的扩展
happened to be called the Rational
Numbers. Let's talk about, first of all, whether we want an extension of the real numbers,
叫做实数。我们先说一下我们是否需要对实数进行扩展
and secondly, if we do,
然后，如果的确需要
what shall we call it, and what properties shall it have?
我们应该叫它什么，它应该有什么性质？
To motivate why we would like the equation, x squared
plus 1 equals 0 to have solutions. And that, of course, is just equivalent to x squared equals minus 1
我们希望x^2 + 1 == 0 有解的动机是什么呢。
Let's go
back to an example that we used when we first introduced exponents in part 1 of our course
让我们回到我们在 课程part 1介绍指数时引入的一个例子
We observed that one of the properties of an
我们观察到
equation like y equals e to the rx where r is a constant
对于方程 y  = e^rx， （r为常数）
t is that if we
differentiate this with respect to x
当我们以x为变量对这个方程求导的时候
the r comes down.But the fact, the e to the rx remains
r 落下来，但是e^rx 保持不变
What this told us was
that in taking derivatives,
这说明在求导的时候
we would get powers of r. But e to the rx would remain. And we use that technique for
solving certain types of second, well, differential equations.
我们会得到r的幂，但是e^rx保持不变。我们用这个技巧解一些二阶微分方程
For example, looking at the equation y double prime plus y equals 0,
比如说，看到方程y'' + y = 0
one technique would be to replace y by e to
the rx. When I differentiate twice, I have an r squared e to the rx here
一个技巧是，用e^rx替换y。当我求导两次的时候，我得到r^2*e^rx
Here is an e to the rx. The e to the rx
cancels out. And I wind up with a polynomial equation for r. And we then solve for the values of r,
这里有一个e^rx, e^rx 被消掉。我得到一个关于r的多项式方程，然后我们求解r
such that this
would be a solution of this.
从而得到方程解
Now back in part 1, because we didn't know non-real numbers. We always fixed it up so that the resulting
equation that we got here would have real numbers for values of r
回到part 1, 因为我们不知道实数以外的数，我们说我们总能得到r为实数的解
by the way, I have chosen this particular
equation for two reasons.
顺便说一下，我选这个例子有两个原因
One is, the values of r can't be real when I get through here. The other is, I already
know an answer to this problem
原因之一在于r不可能是实数，原因之二是我已经知道这个方程的解了。
Remember that if you differentiate sine twice, you get minus sine. I
记得，当你微分sin两次的时候你得到-sin
If you
differentiate cosine twice, you get minus cosine.
如果你微分cos两次，你会得到-cos
Consequently, the second derivative of sine x plus sine x is 0. Second derivative of cosine x plus cosine x is 0.
所以，sin(x)的二阶导加上sin(x) 等于0. cos(x)的二阶导加上cos(x) 等于0.
So
I know at least two solutions to this equation, two real solutions to this equation
所以我知道这个方程的至少两个解，两个实数解。
this equation has physical
meaning because it essentially says, if you think of the parameter as being time here, look at the second
derivative is equal to minus the function itself.
这个方程有物理意义， 它本质上在说，如果你把参数x看成时间的话，这个方程就是
That says that the acceleration is equal to minus the
displacement. And that's a form of simple harmonic motion.
这就是加速度等于负的位移。这就是简谐运动
You see, what I'm trying to establish here is that this does have a real solution
我想说的是，这个方程确有实数解
And the problem itself has real
physical significance
而且问题本身有物理意义
At any rate, if we now try to solve this problem using this technique,
如果我们现在想用这个技巧解这个问题
and remember, again,
I can give you problems where we won't know the answer intuitively
记得，我们可以列出没有直观解的问题
and the values of r will still come out to be imaginary. I simply chose this problem so that we could correlate a so-called imaginary answer with a real answer.
r 依然会是虚数。我选择这个问题仅仅是因为我们可以联系虚数解和实数解。
The idea, again, is I differentiate e to the rx twice. I get this.
我求导e^rx两次，我得到这个
I factor out the e
to the rx, which can't be 0.
我约掉e^rx, 因为它不可能为0
Therefore, it must be that r squared plus 1 is 0,
因此，r^2 +1 肯定是0
or r is equal to plus or minus the
square root of minus 1
或者r == +-√-1
Now you see, so far, I don't know what this thing means. Because there certainly is no real number, which has
this property. Because the square of real numbers have to be positive. They can't be minus 1.
到此，我不知道这个东西的含义，因为它们肯定不是实数，
Let me, for the
sake of argument, invent a number
让我为了这个讨论， 发明一个数
which is equal to the square root of minus 1. I'll call that number i. So r is
equal to plus or minus i.
一个等于-1的平方根的数。我把它称作i。所以r 等于正负i
And if I now remember what equation I'm solving-- it was y equals e to the rx
我们要解的方程，y = e^rx
I can replace r by either i or minus
i. So the two solutions I would get would be y equals e to the ix or y equals e to the minus x.
我可以用i或者-1替换r。从而得到两个方程y=e^ix 或者y=e^-ix
But this is bothering me. Because I really have no real feeling for what I means right now.
但是这会困扰我。因为我没有真实的感受这意味着什么。
What I do know, however, is this,
我知道的是，
that mechanically, this is a solution to a real problem. y double prime plus y
equals zero is a real problem, not an imaginary one.
这是一个真实问题的解，y'' + y = 0 是一个真实的问题，不是一个虚拟的问题。
And by the way, notice mechanically here, taking i to be a
constant, if we still assume that the derivative of e to the x is re to the rx
顺便提到，i为常数，如果我们还是认定e^rx的导数是re^rx。
even when r happens to be non-real,
notice that if I differentiate this thing twice
即使r为非实数。注意到如果我微分两次。
the first time I differentiate, I bring down an i, the second time I
differentiate, I bring down an i
第一次微分的时候，我拿下来一个i，第二次微分的时候，我拿下来一个i。
That gives me i squared, which is minus 1.
那样我会得到i^2， 即-1
This is going to be minus e to the ix.
And if I add on e to the ix, I really do get 0.
这样会是-e^ix， 加上e^ix的话，确实等于0.
Notice also, now, that I do know that a real solution of this equation is y equals cosine x,
另外注意到，y = cos(x)是这个方程的实数解。
or also y equals sine x
或者y = sin(x)
So that somehow or other, I get the feeling that I should exist
所以我感觉到，i 应该存在。
and more to the point, that this expression e to the
ix should somehow be related to sin x and cosine x
而且，这个表达式e^x应该跟sin(x)或者cos(x)有关系
In other words, if I had never been lucky enough to invent
the trigonometric functions, and I want to solve the problem, y double prime plus y equals 0
换句话说，如果我不知道三角函数，又想解答这个y'' + y = 0的问题
and wound up with
this,
得到这个方程
then my feeling is, I must find a real interpretation, a physically real interpretation for each of the ix.
那么我的感觉是，我必须为e^ix找到一个实际的解释，一个物理上的解释
Because I sense that my problem has a solution.
因为我知道我的问题有解
Again, I can take the coward's way out. I can say, if it's going to be this much work, I don't want the problem to
have a solution.
再一次，我可以选择懦弱的方式。我可以说，我不想让这个方程有解
But once I want the problem to have a solution, I must extend the number system.
但是如果我希望方程有解的话，我必须扩展数域
And the
upside of that whole thing is that we now invent something called the Complex Number System.
这样的好处是我们发明了复数系统
First of all, the complex numbers are defined to be the set of all symbols-- let's just call them Symbols for the
time being-- all symbols of the form x plus iy, where x and y are real numbers
第一，复数是指一些符号的集合，让我们现在称它们为符号，所有的x +iy，其中x跟y为实数
And just to refresh our memories
here, i is the symbol which numerically represents the square root of minus 1
回忆一下，i 是-1 的平方根
Notice that the X and the y are
real numbers, though, where by Real, we mean what? The squares are non negative.
注意到x和y是实数，实数的含义是什么？是它们的平方非负
Now you will recall, that in any mathematical system, the thing that you're dealing with is more than a set of
numbers,
在任意数学系统中，我们处理的不只是数的集合
it's a set of numbers or a set of objects together with a structure,
是一个结构与一个数集或者一个物件集合构成的整体
certain rules that tell us how to work
with these elements that make up the set
一些关于这个集合中元素组合的规则
Remember, the difference between a set and a system is a set that's
just a collection of objects. The system is the collection of objects together with how we combine these objects to
form similar objects, et cetera.
记得，集合与系统的区别在于，集合只是一些元素的合集，系统是一些元素的集合以及如何用这些元素构造相似的元素，等等
And what is the structure in this case? Given the two complex numbers, x1 plus iy1 and x2 plus iy2
这里的结构是什么？ 对于两个数x1 +iy1 与x2 +i y2
we define
equality to be sort of component by component.
我们定义复数的等于是复数的各个部分相等
The real parts x1 and x2 must be equal. And the imaginary
parts-- and by the way, just a word of caution here, the imaginary part of a complex number is, by definition, the
coefficient of i.
x1 和x2的实部和虚部都相等。顺带一提，复数的虚部是指i的系数
Notice that the imaginary part is itself a real number. The coefficient of i is the real number y1. What we're saying is we define the definition of equality for complex numbers to be that two complex numbers are equal if and only if their real parts are equal and their imaginary parts are equal.
注意到虚部本身是一个实数。i的系数是实数y1。我们定义复数的相等当且仅当它们的实部与虚部都相等
Secondly, we agree to add two complex numbers, component by component, so to speak. In other words, to add
two complex numbers, we add the two real parts, and we add the two imaginary parts,
第二，我们定义两个复数的加法为两个复数各个部分相加。换句话说，两个复数相加就是它们的实部加实部，虚部加虚部。
OK? That's all this says.
And thirdly, to multiply a complex number by a real number,
第三，用实数乘以一个复数是值
we multiply the real part by the given real number
and the imaginary part by the given real number,
我们用这个实数乘以复数的实部，用这个实数乘以复数的虚部
which is what this third rule says. And all I want to see from this
is that by the very definition of these three structural properties, we have made the complex numbers a twodimensional vector space.
这就是第三条规则，有了这三条规则后复数就构成了二维向量空间
In other words, it means that we can now visualize the complex numbers,
geometrically, in the same way that we could visualize the real numbers geometrically
换句话来说，我们可以用几何的图像表达复数。就像我们可以用几何的图像表达实数一样。
Remember, geometrically-- when we define the real numbers to be those numbers whose squares are non
negatives, we do not need any picture to visualize that. It just happens that the number line, the x-axis, is a very convenient way of visualizing real numbers pictorially.
记得，几何上来讲，当我们定义实数为平方非负的数的时候，我们不需要用图像表示，它正好是数轴，x轴。这是一个方便地表达实数的方法。
What we're saying is that since complex numbers seem to
indicate a two-dimensional vector space, namely, real and imaginary parts which are independent, i
复数组成了一个向量空间，因为，它的实部和虚部是独立的。
it would
appear that the analog for visualizing complex numbers pictorially would be to use the plane. And that's exactly
what we do.
我们可以用一个平面来表示复数。
The idea is this. Given the complex number x plus iy, which we'll call
z,
给定复数z = x+iy,
we visualize z as either the point x comma y in the xy plane-- in other words, notice that the x-axis is the real
axis, meaning it denotes the real part of the complex number. The y-axis is called the imaginary axis,
我们用xy平面上的(x, y) 表示它。换句话说，注意到x轴是实轴, 代表复数的实部。y轴是虚轴
because it
denotes the coefficient of i, the imaginary part, OK
因为它代表了i的系数，虚部
And what we're saying is we can visualize the complex
number x plus iy to be the point x comma y.Or for that matter, the vector that goes from the origin to the point
z, whose components are x and y, meaning what? x plus iy. The components are the real and the imaginary parts
here.
我们想要说的是我们可以用(x, y) 表示复数。或者说，从原点到(x, y)的向量，x +iy。
We can translate this into polar coordinates
我们可以将它翻译成极坐标
meaning that we can measure the point z by its r value and its theta
value. But one important thing to remember is that in polar coordinates,
即我们可以用r和theta表示点z。但是重要的是在极坐标中
it's always assumed that r is positive. Unlike the usual polar coordinates,
r总是正数，不像一般地极坐标
where r could be either positive or negative,
r可正可负。
the idea is that we would like to
identify the absolute value of a complex number with being its distance from the origin. Since we want absolute
value to be non-negative,
我们可以这样表示复数到原点的距离表示复数的绝对值。因为我们希望绝对值是非负的
we simply say that r is the positive square root of x squared plus y squared. And that
names the magnitude of the complex number.
我们说r 是x的平方加上y的平方的平方根。即复数的绝对值。
The angle theta is called the Argument, abbreviated Arg, not to be confused with this funny coincidence of
Argand diagram. This comes from the word Argument, argument.
角theta称作幅角，简写作Arg。
The angle is called the Argument, all right? And if you elect to write the complex number x plus iy as r comma theta,
角度称作幅角，如果你想用(r, theta) 表示复数的话
because of the connection between polar and Cartesian coordinates,
因为极坐标和笛卡尔坐标的联系。
r-- see, x is what? x is r cosine theta. y is r sine theta. So the complex number is
r cosine theta plus ir sine theta. That's what r comma theta denotes.
x是什么？ x 是cos(theta), y是sin(theta)。所以复数是rcos(theta) +i* sin(theta)。这就是（r, theta）所代表的。
Now using this as background-- so we now have what? We've invented, at least abstractly, a system of numbers
called the Complex Numbers. And by the way, let me point out here
以此为背景，我们有了什么？我们发明了，至少抽象地，一个数的系统，叫做复数。顺便，让我指明
that don't use the word Imaginary too
strongly. There is certainly nothing imaginary about this geometric interpretation
不要强烈地用“虚”这个字，因为复数的几何表达肯定不是虚的
What may be imaginary is I
may not have a place where I want to use these kind of numbers. But believe me, we wouldn't have made a
whole block of material about these numbers if there weren't real interpretations
所谓“虚”可以指在有的情形下我们不能使用这个数。但是相信我，我们不会在没有实际解释的情况下发明一种数。
of the so-called complex
numbers. This is a perfectly real geometric interpretation. So far, we have established the fact that this interpretation gives
us a vector space. But the complex numbers have an additional structure as well, namely
这是完全真实的几何解释。到此为止，我们建立了复数的向量空间。但是复数还有其他的结构。
if I saw the two
complex numbers, a plus bi times-- and c plus di, and I multiplied them-- remember now, a, b, c, and d are real-
如果我们拿到两个复数（a +bi），（c +di），将这两个数相乘，记住，a, b, c, d是实数
I
would like to believe that the rules of ordinary algebra still apply here. I would want this times
this, this times this, this times this, and this times this
普通的代数规则在这里依然成立
Notice that a times c as ac. bi times di should be bd times i squared, if the ordinary rules of arithmetic are to
apply. Since i squared is minus 1, this term becomes minus bd
这样的话，
Since a, c, b, and d are real numbers, this is a real number, right?
因为a, c, b, d 是实数，这也是一个实数，对吧？
Correspondingly, the coefficient of-- the multiplier of i, the coefficient of i is what? bc plus ad, which is also a real number. So if we make up this definition of multiplication for complex numbers
同样的，i的系数是什么？(bc + ad)。也是一个实数。所以我们有了复数乘法的定义
we have made sure that the rules of arithmetic for complex numbers parallel the rules for real numbers
我们确定实数算术运算的规则同样适用于复数。
And by the way, it's very important here to make the aside that this is a crucial result.  Notice that among the complex numbers
顺带一提，这是一个非常重要的性质，因为在复数中包括了实数
the real numbers are included, namely, thinking of it geometrically, if
you look at the plane,
比如，从几何角度来看，如果你看到复平面
the real numbers are those points in the plane which lie along the x-axis.
实数就是那些在实轴上的数
It's the same as
saying that when you extended the integers to form the rational numbers, the rational numbers included the
integers.
就是当我们扩充整数到实数的时候，实数是包含整数的
In other words, if I look at the number 3, I can think of it as the integer 3. . I could also think of it as the ratio 3
divided by 1
换句话说，如果我们看到数字3，它可以是整数3，也可以是3除以1的分数。
you see? And therefore, I would like whatever rules I have for the complex numbers to remain valid
if the complex numbers happen to be real. I
看到了吗？因此，我希望复数的运算规则在复数正好是实数的时候依然成立
It would be terrible to have two different rules for multiplication, one
for real numbers and one for complex numbers,
如果实数和复数有两套不同的运算规则的话将是非常糟糕的
and then given two real numbers, when I multiply them, I get one
answer if I think of them as being real, and another answer if I think of them as being complex.
这样当我们拿到两个实数的时候，当我们把它们看做实数会有一个答案，看做复数又会有另一个答案
At any rate, the important point is with this as motivation, I have a way of defining the product of two complex
numbers to be a complex number. I don't mean that these things are equal to r, so they simply stand for Real.
This is real plus i times a real, which is a complex number.
总之，以此为动机。我有了定义复数乘法的方法。
I don't mean that these things are equal to r, so they simply stand for Real.
This is real plus i times a real, which is a complex number.
我不是说这些数等于r，这表示实数。这是实数加上i乘以实数，即一个复数
A very special case occurs when you take the complex number a plus bi and multiply it by a minus bi, the same
number only changing the plus to a minus.
一个非常特别的例子是当你拿到实数a + bi然后乘以a - bi。
Notice that we would get what? The sum and difference here gives us
the sum of difference of two squares.
注意到你会得到什么？两个数的平方差
It's going to be what? a squared minus b squared i squared. But since i
squared is minus 1, minus b squared i squared is minus b squared times minus 1, which is plus b squared.
得到了什么？ a^2 - b^2 * i^2.因为i^2==-1， 即a^2 + b^2
And
notice, therefore, if you multiply a plus bi, which is a complex number, by this other complex number, a minus bi,
you get a squared plus b squared, which is a non-negative real number.
注意到，因此，如果你用复数乘以a+bi， 另一个复数，你可以得到一个非负的实数。
In particular, if you think back to the geometric interpretation of this,
特别地，如果你回想起几何表达的话
the point a plus bi in the plane is a comma b. And the distance of a comma b from the origin is the square root of a squared plus b squared.
点（a, b）到原点的距离是a^2 +b^2.
So this product
is actually the square of the magnitude, the absolute value of a plus bi.
所以这个乘积其实是a + bi绝对值的平方，
This little gizmo is so important that it's given a special name.
这个小东西很重要，重要到我们给它取了一个特别的名字。
By definition, given any complex number z, written
in the form x plus iy, the complex conjugate of z, called z bar-- not to be confused with a z with a bar underneath
定义，对于复数 z = x + iy， 它的共轭复数 z bar，
that we were using to denote vectors-- but the complex conjugate z bar is what you get by just changing the plus
sign here to a minus.In other words, the complex conjugate of x plus iy is x minus iy. And geometrically, all this means is, you see, when you change the sign of the imaginary part,
是将这里的正号变成负号。即x +i y 的共轭是x - iy。几何的讲，就是改变虚部的符号
remember, the imaginary part is the y-axis.
记得，虚部是y轴
You're just
reflecting the number symmetrically with respect to the x-axis. You're leaving the x-coordinate alone. And you're
changing the y-coordinate to minus y.
就是关于x轴的对称点，x坐标不变，y坐标变号。
In polar coordinates, what you're saying is a complex number and its conjugate are the same distance from the
origin. But in one case, the angle is theta. And in the other case, the angle is minus theta.
在极坐标中，这就是复数和它的共轭到原点的距离相等。但是角度一个是theta,一个是-theta
One of the many
applications of complex conjugates-- I'll give you some of these other applications in the exercises. But for now,
what I think is important is a simple one
我会在练习题中提供更多关于复数共轭的练习，现在提供一个简单的
that essentially shows us how we find the quotient of two complex
numbers
求两个复数的商
Quite simply, sparing you the details, if I have c plus di divided by a plus bi
很简单，如果我有(c+di) / (a+bi）
我用分母的共轭乘以分子和分母
What will that do for me? Well, when I multiply the two factors in the numerator, I'm going to get a real part, namely, ac plus bd.
这样我会得到什么？对于分子的实数部分，我将会得到(ac +bd)
In other words, it's minus bd i
squared. But i squared is minus 1.
其实是-bd*i^2，但是i^2是-1
So I'm going to get ac plus bd. I'm going to get an imaginary part, which is ad minus bc. But the denominator will
just be a squared plus b squared,
所以是(ac +bd),虚数部分是(ad - bc)，分母是a^2 +b^2
which is a real number. In other words, what this tells me is I can now write the quotient of two complex numbers in the form what-- a real number plus i times a real number.
分母是一个实数。换句话说，我可以将两个复数的商写作一个实数加上i乘以另一个实数的形式。实际上，只有当a 和b都为0的时候我不能这样做
a or b must be unequal to 0. Because if both and b are 0, this is a 0 denominator, which I don't allow myself to divide by.
实际上，只有当a 和b都为0的时候我不能这样做。因为除以0是非法的
And the only way both a and b can be 0 is if the complex number is 0 plus 0i, which is the number 0. So I'm
saying, again, just like in the real case, I still can't divide by 0.
只有当复数是0 +0i的时候a 和b 才都是0，就像实数一样，除以0是非法的。
Anyway, to give you a more practical illustration to see this with numbers-- not practical, but, at least, concrete--
举一个实际的例子
3 plus 2i divided by 4 plus i, I simply multiply numerator and denominator by 4 minus i.
3 +2 i 除以 4 +i， 我将分子分母同乘(4 - i)
You see, what that does
is downstairs, I get 4 squared, which is 16, minus i squared, which is plus 1,
这样我会得到，4^2，16  减去i^2 ， 1
16 plus 1 is 17. The real part is going
to be what? Here's 12. 2i times minus i is plus 2 is 14.
实部是多少？16 加 1 等于17。这里是12，2 i乘以-i是2， 14
8i minus 3i is 5i. So this quotient, 3 plus 2i times 4 plus i, is
14/17 plus 5/17 i. And by the way, as a trivial check, a
8i减去3i是5i。所以这个商，3 +2i 乘以4 + i，是14/17 +5/17i。作为一个小的检查
and you can do this if you wish for an exercise,
你也可以用作练习
simply take the answer that we got here, multiply it by the denominator, 4 plus i here, and actually check that that product comes out to be 3 plus 2i.
将答案乘以分母(4_+ i)，看看乘积是否是(3 +2i)
At any rate, this use of complex conjugates shows us that when you divide two complex numbers, the result will
be a complex number, except for division by 0
用共轭复数向我们展示了如何将两个复数相除，结果也是复数，除了除0之外
to solve 2x equals 3 required that the process of taking the
quotient of two integers, and the quotient of two integers did not have to be an integer
为了解答2 * x = 3需要拿两个整数的商，但是两个整数的商不一定是整数
Notice on the other hand,
that the quotient of two real numbers is a real number, as long as the denominator is not 0. And the quotient of
two complex numbers is a complex number, except for division by 0.
注意到两个实数的商是实数，只要除数不为零。两个复数的商是复数，只要除数不为零
While we're talking about multiplication, a very enlightening thing happens if we think of multiplication in terms of polar coordinates,
当我们用极坐标的形式看待乘法的时候，会有非常有趣的发现
namely, take the two numbers, which in polar coordinates, are r1 comma theta 1 and r2 comma theta 2.  Now again, remember from our Argand diagram what it means to say that the complex number has polar coordinates r1 comma theta 1.
两个数，(r1, theta1), (r2, theta2)，
Remember, the complex number is written in the form x plus iy. The xcoordinate is r1 cosine theta 1. The y-coordinate is r1 sine theta 1.
记得，复数的形式是（x +iy），x 坐标是r1 * cos(theta1), y坐标是（r1sin(theta1）
At any rate, this product, in terms of the
standard notation, the x plus iy form, says we're multiplying these two numbers together.
这个乘积，用标准的形式表达，表明我们在乘以这两个数
And using our rule for multiplication, multiplying term by term, and remembering that i squared is minus 1,
用我们的乘法规则，记得i^2 == -1
observe that if we collect the terms here-- and I'll leave the details for you to verify at your leisure-- we wind up
with r1 r2 being a common factor.
我们得到
The real part is r1 r2 times cosine theta 1 cosine theta 2 minus sine theta 1 sine theta 2. The minus coming, because i squared is minus 1.
实数部分是r1, r2 乘以cos(theta1)cos(theta2) - sin(theta1) sin(theta2)，负号是从i^2 == - 1得到的
The imaginary part is r1 r2 sine theta 1 cosine
theta 2 sine theta 2 cosine theta 1.
虚部是(r1r2(sin(theta1)cos(theta2) + sin(theta2)cos(theta1)
Remember, theta is a real number.
记得，theta是一个实数
If we recall our geometric-- trigonometric definitions, cosine theta 1 cosine
theta 2 minus sine theta 1 sine theta 2 is cosine theta 1 plus theta 2.This expression this sine theta 1 plus theta
2.
用三角函数的定义， cosine theta 1 cosine
theta 2 - sine theta 1 sine theta 2 = cosine theta 1 plus theta 2.这个表达式等于 sine theta 1 + theta2.
And remembering now that in polar form, what we're saying is what? This is the complex number whose
magnitude is r1 r2 and whose argument is theta 1 plus theta 2.
用极坐标表达，这个一个幅值为r1r2，幅角为theta1 +theta2的复数
And putting these two steps together, what it
says is that to multiply two complex numbers, the same definition of multiplication that we were using before, i
将这两步合并，乘以两个复数，跟我们刚刚定义的复数乘积一样
if
we interpret this in terms of polar coordinate, it says, look at, to multiply two complex numbers [INAUDIBLE]
lengths,
如果我们从极坐标的角度理解
you simply do what? Multiply the two lengths to get the resulting length of the product and add the two
arguments, the two angles.
你只需要简单地乘以两个长度，加上两个幅角
That's a rather interesting result. You see, for example, if we now want to think of the complex numbers as being
vectors, this gives us a third vector product
这是一个很有趣的结论。如果把复数想象成向量的话，
that we had never talked about before and which I'll reinforce in the
learning exercises. The idea is that using this as a model, and here's another real application, why not define a
new product of two vectors
我会在练习题中强化这一点。为什么不将两个向量的乘积定义成
obtained by multiplying the two lengths and adding the two angles? And the point
was, that in our physical examples, there was really no motivation to invent this vector definition, in the same
way that we could define the dot product and the cross product for complex numbers.
将它们的长度相乘角度相加呢？
对于我们的实际例子来说，没有这个向量定义的动机。我们同样可以定义复数的点积和叉积
Because after all, they are viewed as vectors in the plane. But again, we have no great practical application for
this. So we don't bother doing it.
因为复数可以看出平面上的向量。但是，这样做没有实际作用。所以我们并没有这样的定义。
By the way, just for kicks here, I thought you might enjoy the aside that this
little interesting result explains why the product of two negative numbers
顺带一提，这里可以有趣的解释为什么两个负数的乘积是正数
happen to be positive. Remember a
negative number, if r has to-- see, a negative number lies on the real axis. And if r has to be positive, that means
you're measuring in the direction of the negative x-axis,
负数在数轴的负半轴
which means that the polar angle is 180 degrees. If you
multiply two numbers whose angles are 180 degrees, if you add the two angles, you get what? 360 degrees.
对于它的极坐标来说，幅角是180度。两个幅角为180度的数相乘，结果的幅角为360度。
You see what I'm driving at here? In other words, if I multiply two numbers in polar form, each of whose angles is
180,
如果对两个极坐标表示的数相乘，幅角都为180度
the product will have the angle equal to 360
乘积的角度为360度
you see? And that puts you back on the positive real axis. And
so you have such real interpretations as y in terms of complex numbers, we can explain very nicely what it
means for the product of two negatives to be a positive.
这样结果回到了正半轴。这样我们可以很好的解释为什么两个负数的乘积为正数。
By the way, we can carry this result further if we had n factors written in polar form
顺带一提，当我们有n个因子的话我们可以将结论推得更远
Then to multiply these n
factors, we would simply, by induction, so to speak, multiply the n magnitudes together and add the n angles. And a very interesting special case i
乘以这n个因子，用数学归纳的方式，就是乘以这n个数的幅值，加上n个幅角
e is if all of the factors happen to be equal-- in other words, if we want to raise
the complex number written in polar form as r comma theta
一个有趣的例子是如果所有因子相等，即我们想求一个复数的n次幂
to the n-th power, a very interesting thing is that r
comma theta to the n-th power is what? You multiply the magnitude. So the magnitude of the product will be r to
the n.
结果是什么呢？结果的幅值是r^n
You add the angles. So the angle of the product, the argument will be n times theta.A special case of the special case is if r equals 1.
你将幅角相加，所以结果的幅角是n *theta。一个特例是r 等于1的时候
即复数的极坐标形式为（1，theta）
when raised to the n-th power, is that complex number in polar form 1 comma n
theta.
它的n次幂为(1, n*theta)
And by the way, again, remember what this thing means? To say that the complex number is 1 comma
theta means what? That the distance from the origin is 1 and the angle is theta. S
顺带一提，（1，theta）意味着什么呢？意味着到原点的距离为1，角度为theta
See, that was what we mean by
1 comma theta over here.
这是（1，theta）的含义
And notice that in Cartesian form, that makes this length cosine theta and this length sine theta. So i comma
theta is cosine theta plus i sine theta.
在笛卡尔坐标系中，这个长度为cos(theta), 这个长度为sin(theta)。所以(1, theta)就是cos(theta) +sin(theta)
At any rate, translating both of these into Cartesian form,
将这些翻译成笛卡尔坐标的形式
we wind up with a very famous result, called De Moivre's theorem. . In my high school, it was called "De Moyvre's" theorem.
我们可以得到一个非常著名的结论，棣莫弗公式
But it's De Moivre's theorem. And it simply says that cosine theta plus i sine theta to the n is cosine n theta plus i sine ntheta.
它指的是(cos(x)+isin(x))^n=cos(nx)+isin(nx)
That result may not seem that remarkable to you. But let me give you another example using this result
that shows how we can get real results using imaginary numbers.
这个结论可能没什么了不起的。让我举例另外一个用虚数得到实数的例子
Let me take the special case n equals 2,
让我们看看当n = 2的情况
just for the sake of argument. If I take n equals 2, this gives me cosine
theta plus i sine theta squared equals cosine 2 theta plus i sine 2 theta.
如果n=2的话，这会给我(cos(theta) +i sin(theta) )^2 == sin(2*theta)+cos(2*theta)
This says what? The real part of this is
cosine squared theta minus sine squared theta. Again, it's i squared sine squared theta,
这说明了什么？ 实部是cos^2(theta) ^2 - sin^2(theta)。再一次，是i^2*sin^2(theta)
which is minus sine
squared theta. The imaginary part is 2 sine theta cosine theta.
就是-sin^2(theta)。虚部是2*sin(theta) *cos(theta)
So if I square this, I get cosine squared theta minus sine squared theta plus i2 sine theta cosine theta
所以我平方这个，我得到cos^2(theta)- sin^2(theta)+i *2*sin(theta)*cos(theta)
By De
Moivre's theorem, that equals cosine 2 theta plus i sine 2 theta.
根据棣莫弗公式，它等于cos(2*theta)+i sin(2*theta)
We saw that the only way that two complex
numbers can be equal is if the real parts are equal and if the imaginary parts are equal.
我们说两个复数相等是指它们的实部和虚部都相等
Comparing the real parts and comparing the imaginary parts, we get that sine 2 theta equals 2 sine theta cosine theta. Cosine 2 theta is cosine squared theta minus sine squared theta. Notice, by the way, that these are real results.
比较它们的实部与虚部，我们得到sin(2*theta)= 2sin(theta)cos(theta)。cos(2*theta) = cos^2(theta)- sin^2(theta)。注意到，这些都是实数
And also, notice, by the way, that even though these may look like old hat to you, I could just as easily, for
example, I could have picked n 5 here or 6. And in fact, I will do that
注意到，这些公式可能老套，但是我们可以选择 n == 5 或者 n == 6. 实际上，我们会在练习题中做这些
in the learning exercises. The point being that, what, I can raise this to the fifth power, compare this with cosine 5 theta plus i sine 5 theta, and wind up with real identities, in fact, for what?
我可以用它的5次幂，与cos(5*theta)+ i * sin(5*theta) 相比，得到结果
Sine n theta and cosine n theta for any whole number value of n. See, I'm trying to hammer home the fact that as
we're doing the complex number arithmetic,
sin(n*theta)和cos(n*theta)。回到我们在做复数运算的事实。
don't forget that this stuff does have real applications, and we haven't even started to scratch the surface yet. This is just our baby lecture introducing the arithmetic of
complex numbers. We haven't even gotten to anything like algebra or calculus yet.
这些东西都是有实际应用的，我们才刚刚接触它的表面。我们只介绍了复数的运算，没有涉及到代数和微积分
Wait till that happens, and you're really going to see some nice applications.
At any rate, by the way, the polar form of multiplication that leads to a very interesting way of extracting roots of
complex numbers.
到那时我们可以看到一些实际的应用。顺带一提，复数的极坐标表示提供了一个很好的求复数根的方式
For example, suppose I want to find the sixth root of i. In other words, what complex number,
raised to the sixth power, gives i? I
比如说，假设我们想找i 的六次方根。即什么数的六次方是i?
In fact, is there such a complex number? After all, we could raise real numbers
to powers. But one of the reasons that we had to invent the complex numbers is that we couldn't extract the
square root of minus 1.
真的存在这样的数吗？毕竟，我们可以取实数的幂。但是我们发明复数的一个原因是我们不能取-1的平方根
There was no real number whose square was minus 1. The question now is there a
complex number, which when raised to the sixth power, equals i?
没有实数的平方是-1.现在的问题是是否存在一个复数，它的六次方等于i
One way of doing this is to say, OK, let's assume there is a complex number. We'll call it x plus iy, which when
raised to the sixth power, equals i. In other words, the sixth root the i is x plus iy
假设存在这样一个数x +iy的话，
And let's see if we can solve for
x and y.
我们试一下能不能解出x和y
One way of doing this is to raise both sides here to the sixth power, in which case we see that i has to be x plus iy to the sixth power.
一个方法是将两边都取六次幂。i 等于x+ iy 的六次幂
On the other hand, i is written as 0 plus 1i.
另一边， i == 0 +1 i
If I raise this to the sixth power, I don't know if you've noticed this,
every time I raise i to an even power, I get a real number
注意到每次我取偶数次幂的时候，我得到一个实数
Why? Because i squared is minus 1.
为什么？因为i^2 == -1
Therefore, i to the fourth is i squared squared, which is minus 1 squared, which is 1.
因此，i ^4 == 1
i to the sixth is i to the fourth times i squared,
which is 1 times i squared, which is minus 1
i ^ 6 等于i^4 乘以i^2.等于-1
And in the same way, if I take i cubed
同样的，如果我取i的立方的话
that's what? i squared times i, which is minus i. In other words, the even
powers of i are real, the odd powers of i give me back plus or minus i.
得到-i.换句话说，偶数次幂是实数，奇数次幂得到正或负1
So if I raise this to the sixth power and collect terms, I'll get a certain number of real terms and a certain number of purely imaginary terms.
如果我取六次幂，我会得到几次实数和几次纯虚数
In fact, using the binomial theorem and raising this to the sixth power and separating the terms for you in
advance, I wind up with what?
事实上，用二项式定理将它取六次幂，我会得到什么？
blabla, 就是运用二项式定理。
noticing that all of these terms will turn out to be real. All of these
terms will be purely imaginary.
注意到这些项是实数，这些项是虚数
In other words, getting rid of the i's to the best of my ability.
See, squaring over here, this is a minus y squared term. This is just y to the fourth. This is i to the sixth, which is
the same as i squared. Because i to the fourth is 1.  i to the sixth is i fourth times i squared, which is i squared
总之尽量去掉i
So this just comes out as minus 1, et cetera.
And making these translations, we wind up with the complicated algebraic system
所以我们得到-1等等。我们得到一个复杂的代数系统
that to find x and y, we must
be able to solve this system of equations. In other words, the root part must be 0, the imaginary part must be 1,
为了找到x 和y,我们要解这一系列方程。实部必须是0，虚部必须是1
all right? Now at this stage of the game, not only may it seem difficult to solve this, but it may be that there are
no real values of x and y which solve this. And if I can't find x and y
看起来求解非常困难，而如果我们不能解出x 和y 的话
if there are no values for x and y, it means
that x plus iy doesn't exist.
如果没有x和y的话，复数x + i y 不存在
Well, here's where I wanted to show you the tremendous power of polar coordinates. You see, in polar
coordinates, how would I write i?
这里就可以看出极坐标的威力了。在极坐标中，我们怎么表示i
I is what? It's magnitude is 1.
它的幅值是1
. See, it's the 0.0 comma 1 in the Argand diagram.
It's magnitude is 1. And it's argument is pi over 2.
是复平面上的（0，1）这一点。幅值为1，幅角为pi/2
By the way, again, I'm in this trouble with multiple angles. You see, it's only pi over 2. It could be 5 pi over 2, 9 pi over 2, et cetera. Every time I go through 2 pi, I come back to the same point. I'm going to mention that in a moment.
顺便说，这里的角度可以指多个，可以说pi/ 2, 也可以是5pi/2，等等。每次我经过2pi，我回到原处
But the idea is, look at, this is what I want. This is i and I want the 6th root of i. Let's assume that the answer can be written in polar coordinates
注意到，这就是我想要的。这是i, 这是i 的六次方根
f I write it in polar coordinates, the answer is r comma theta. All I've
got to do now is solve for r and theta. And I claim, believe it or not, that that's trivial, n
如果我写成极坐标形式，答案是（r, theta）。我想解出r和theta。我提出，这个解是好求的
namely, given this, I raise
both sides to the sixth power.
If I do that, I wind up here with i, which just, to get this all on one line, I just repeat this. This is 1 comma pi over 2
in polar coordinates
我取两边的六次幂。我得到这个
And this is r comma theta to the sixth power. But the beauty of multiplication in polar
coordinates is that r comma theta to the sixth power is r to the sixth comma 6 theta
这是(r,theta)的六次方。但是极坐标乘积的好处是(r, theta)的六次方是(r^6, 6 * theta)
The magnitude is this-- so in
other words, you multiply the magnitudes, and you add the angles.
幅值相乘，幅角相加
Therefore, what this tells me is, remember, r must be real. There is only one real number, which when raised to
the sixth power, is 1.
记住，r必须是实数，它的六次方是1
And that's 1 itself
这就是1本身
See, the n-th root of any positive number
任何正数的n次方根
has exactly one real solution.
That's why we can always find the r. In this case, I picked the simple example where r turns out to be 1.
有唯一的实数解。所以我们总能解出r。在这里，为了简单起见，取r == 1
See, minus 1 also raised to the sixth power is 1. But that doesn't count. Because we agreed that r had to be positive. r was measuring the magnitude of the complex number, so r must be 1 by virtue of the fact that r is greater than r equal to 0.
-1的六次方也是1.但是我们规定r必须为正。r是复数的幅值，所以必须大于等于0
That eliminates minus 1.
这样-1被排除
Now 6 theta can either be pi over 2 or 5 pi over 2, et cetera. The important point being that we now tack on the 2 pi k. Because notice that as this changes by 360 degrees, theta only changes by 60 degrees. Because 6 theta is changing by 360.
6*theta可以是pi/2, 5*pi / 2等等。我们加上2pi*k, 因为将它改变360度的话，theta只改变60度。因为6 *theta 会变化360度
Therefore, you see, we're going to get a whole bunch of theta values that work this way. And again, I'll explain this in more detail as we go through the exercises on this unit.
因此，我们会得到很多theta的解。我会在这个单元的练习题中详细描述。
But the idea is what? If I keep tacking on multiples of 2 pi, what I'm saying is r must be 1, and theta is what?
如果我一直加上2pi的倍数的话。r必须是1，theta是多少？
It's pi over 12 plus what? 2 pi k over 6 pi over 3k, 60
是pi / 12 +2 *pi *k / 6 * pi ~~~~
I essentially, in terms of angles, tack on 60 degree increments here. To make a long story short, r must be 1. But theta could either be pi over 12, 5 pi over 12, 9 pi over 12, 13 pi over 12. See, I'm adding on 4 pi over 12 each time, pi over 3,
本质上，对于幅角来说，每次加60度。r必须是1，theta可以是pi/12, 5pi / 12, 9pi / 12， 每次加4*pi/ 12， pi/3
60 degrees, in degree measure. 17 pi over 12, 21 pi over 12. The next one would be 25 pi over 12. But I hope you can see that that's the same as, position-wise, 1 comma pi over 12
即60度。17pi/12, 21pi / 12.下一步是25pi/12。但是我想你们可以看出来它跟(1, pi/12)，（1， 21pi/12）是同样的
gives me the same thing as 1 comma 25 pi over 12. But all six of these angles give medifferent positions.
这六个角度给我不同的位置
Just by way of illustration, pi over 12 turns out to be 15 degrees.
只是为了描述，pi/12 等于15度
What this says is that one of the six roots of i, geometrically, is what? It's that complex number, which is 1 unit from the origin. That means it's on the circle of radius 1, centered at the origin
这说明对于i的六个根。从几何角度来看？它是距离原点一个单元长的。即在单元圆上。
And the angle must be 15 degrees. The argument is 15 degrees.And by the way, just to check this out that this really is at 1 comma pi over 12 really is an answer here.
角度必须是15度。为了证实1, pi/12真的是答案
How do you raise a complex number to a power if we view it as a length?
我们怎么取复数的幂呢
So I'm still going to be on the circle.
它的结果还会在这个圆上
When I multiply, I add angles. So when
I raise this to the sixth power, I'm taking, what, 15 degrees six times is 90 degrees. And that puts me right up
where i is supposed to be.
当我相乘的时候，我加上角度。所以当我取六次幂的时候，15度的6倍是90度。这样我得到了i
In other words, to this thing backwards, so to speak, I know that 6 times the angle I'm looking for must be 90.
反过来做，我知道6 乘以这个角度等于90度
So the angle itself must be 15. For example, if I was looking for the eighth root of i, I would do what? I
所以这个角一定是15度。另一个例子，如果我想找i的8次方根，我会怎么做呢？
I would know
that when I add the angle to itself 8 times, I want 90. So the angle would have had to been 90 over 8. And again,
I'll leave this for you as exercises. The point is that geometrically,
我知道这个解的幅角乘以8等于90度。所以解的幅角是90/8.这可以作为练习。要点是几何地讲
the sixth roots of i are all equally spaced points. The first one is the point 1 comma pi over 12. And the rest are spaced equally along the circle at 60 degree intervals. You see, it breaks the circle up
i的六次方根在圆上均匀分布。第一个点是(1, pi/12)，剩余的点以60度的间隔等分圆。可以看到，
into six equal parts. I come back to here. Notice that, for example, if I take this one, which is 75 degrees,
它们将圆划分成六等分。当我回到这里的时候，注意到，比如说，如果看到75度
if I take 75 degrees 6 times, notice that I come
back, what, 75 times 6 is 450. It means I go all the way around and come back to i when I raise this to the sixth power.
拿75度六次的时候，就是450度。即取六次幂等于从圆上转一周
To help you see this geometrically, I'll pick-- of these six, one of these happens to be very easy, at least, to me. 9
pi over 12 is 3 pi over 4, which happens to be 135 degrees.
为了那好的从几何上来看，我从这六个点中选9*pi / 12， 即3*oi / 4, 135度
And i-- 1 comma 3 pi over 4 is cosine 3 pi over 4 plus i
sine 3 pi over 4.
（1， 3pi/4）是cos(3*pi/ 4 +sin(3*pi/4)
The cosine of 3 pi over 4 is minus 1 over square root of 2. The sine is plus 1 over square root of
2.
cos(3*pi/4) 等于 -1/√2, sin(3*pi/4) 等于 +1/√2
So in typical x plus iy form, one of the roots is 1 over the square root of 2 times minus 1 plus i. In other words, the real part of this complex number is minus 1 over the square root of 2. The imaginary part is 1 over the square root of 2.
所以复数的实部是-1/√2， 虚部是1/√2
And I leave it, again, as a voluntary exercise for you to do to actually raise this to the sixth power and
find, amazingly enough, that you do get 1 for an answer-- i for an answer
将它留作练习，取它的六次幂，看看答案是否是1
Now you see, I just picked one particular example. But this would have worked for any roots that I wanted to extract. And this is very important from a mathematical point of view. The complex numbers are closed, with respect to extracting roots
我只取了一个例子。但是任何次方根都可以用这种方法获取。这是非常重要的，这说明复数取次方根运算是成环的
And let me summarize that for a part of today's lesson over here. The idea is that one
of the reasons that we had to invent the fractions after we knew the integers
总结今天的课程，在有了整数以后发明分数的一个原因是
整数的除法运算是不成环的
was the fact that the integers were
not closed with respect to division
One of the reasons that we had to invent the complex numbers after we had the real numbers was that the real
numbers were not closed with respect to extracting roots
我们在有了实数以后想发明复数的一个原因是实数对于求根运算不成环
What I've just shown you in terms of a particular
example is that the complex numbers are closed with respect to extracting roots. This means that, in particular,
the basic operations that are involved in solving polynomial equations
我们刚刚看到复数对于求根运算是成环的。这意味着，对于求解多项式方程而言
in other words, what you have to do is
solve a polynomial equation, nothing more than the basic operations of adding, subtracting, multiplying, dividing,
raising the powers, and extracting roots. All of these operations are closed with respect to the complex numbers.
加法，减法，乘法，取幂，求根。所有这些运算对于复数都是成环的
And what this means is if you wanted to write a polynomial equation which had complex numbers as coefficient s,you would not have to invent any more complex numbers. Y
这意味着如果你用复数作为系数构造多项式方程的话，你不会发明新的复数
You would not have to invent a new number system to
solve this equation, namely, any polynomial with complex coefficients has complex roots.
你不会需要发明新的数来解这个方程，任何复数系数的多项式方程有复数根
And I think that's
enough for today. I want you to drill now on the exercises.
Next time, we will talk about functions using complex numbers. At any rate, until next time, goodbye.
这就是今天的全部内容，现在我们来讲练习题吧。下节课，我们会将用复数构成的函数。拜拜